We are going to make a keto friendly chocolate
orange ice cream but we're going to reverse it,
and do orange ice cream with chocolate chips
[Music]
This is the second time I filmed this, I lost
some of the footage and I just couldn't make it
work so here we go again. Which is actually
fine because it's enabled me to make just a
tiny little adjustment to make it even better
so nice and easy keto friendly means low carb,
high fat that is where we are now.
I really wanted to use real oranges for this,
orange zest, but they had all gone off so we're
going to use orange extract. Now if you don't use
the orange extract and you want to use the orange
zest, that is absolutely fine just go ahead and
don't use this, just put in one half an orange
zest the recipe will go ever so slightly harder
but not enough to be of detriment to the result.
So less chit and chat, let's get on with that.
For the keto orange chocolate chip you
are going to need, up on the screen,
here we go 264g of cream, 119g of
water, 55g of Allulose, 54g of inulin,
5g of orange extract (or zest of half an orange),
5g of guar gum and then your chocolate chips,
somewhere between 25 and 50g of milk chocolate.
I'm going to make this a cold process with guar
gum so we don't have to heat it up. We've
got our tub ready we've got our scales ready
so let's get everything weighed out. Let's get
the cream out the........ fridge not that one,
so much cream in there...... 264g of cream
as normal cup measurements on the screen
264g of cream nice, 119g of water I'm
just going to go straight out the tap,
119g.... my battery is running out of my scale so
we're going to have to hurry up 55g of allulose
has it given up?..... into that we're going to
add 54g of inulin and into that we are going
to add our Guar gum or as Americans like say
Guarrrr Gum ;) say it how you like like... so
and with that done we can now just
gently mix those powders together
again we just do this to break up the
guar gum the stabilizer whatever as this
is cold process if you want to heat this
up and use your hot process stabilizer,
then just mix all the ingredients together and
heat it up to your 80°C to 85°C or 180-185°F,
that will do the same thing but sometimes I like
it to make it nice and easy. A lump of something
there..... there we go. So with that done we're
going to add the dry ingredients into the wet
ingredients if you're using the orange zest you
put it in now and ideally you'd want to leave it
in the refrigerator for a few hours just to let
those orange oils come out of that zest and then
after you done that then you can put it in the
freezer. You can just pour it straight into there
then put it in the freezer when it's ready .If you
put it in the freezer straight away, you won't get
a strong orange flavor so it's worth doing but as
we're using the extract today we're going straight
in 5g of orange extract. People always ask me what
extracts I use, this is what I use, Neilson Massey
extracts pretty much exclusively unless I've made
it myself. I make my own extracts where I can and
where I can't or can't be bothered, then it's
Nielsen Massey, you can buy them everywhere,
literally everywhere, buy them on Amazon, buy
them you know in supermarkets and Specialty baking
stores, all over the place. It's an American brand
I think.... yeah Illinois it's American brand
and I know for a fact that it's available in
Europe, pretty much in all supermarkets
Sainsburys, Tesco's, Co-op um Lidl and
Aldi ...... don't know maybe. There we go
the the gum has started to thicken that base
ever slightly, so that's perfect that's
ready to go into our container straight
in ..... perfect amount this equates to 500g
which fills your ninja creamy tub right up
to the line perfectly so, lovely smell of
orange seal that up pop it in the freezer.
We are on the next day ,we're going to
get this Orange Keto ice cream spun up
and whilst the machine is running we're
going to get out our milk chocolate this
is valhrona milk chocolate but just use a
good quality milk chocolate that is fine,
it's been in the freezer we're going to get out
a chopping board this is my kids chopping board
and we're going to cut this up nice nice
and small make sure there's some really
small pieces if you like large chunks make
it large cut it up to the size that you want
to eat it at so just in case you didn't read
the screen this is milk chocolate it's about
50 g of it I kept it in the freezer
get it nice and hard so I can chop it
up let's
get a spoon and just get it in
there like
so and back on and
[Music]
sometimes that feels like that goes on way too
long there we go leave that there just so people
remember that this is a keto recipe let's get
some in the bowl, gorgeous smelling orange Keto
ice cream with milk chocolate chips
throughout valhrona milk chocolate
chips perfect smells delicious let's try some
excellent, perfect combination of
that orange ice cream you get a much
more natural orange flavor doing
it this way rather than you know
a chocolate orange chocolate so if you like
really strong orange then you can add a bit
more extract but you might have to reduce
the allulose, good quality milk chocolate man
delicious excluding the chocolate because
you might use a different one these are
the macros for this keto orange ice cream.
So per 100g we've got 17g of fat, 4.18g of carbs,
1.8g of sugar, 0.7g of fiber and 1.4g of protein.
There you go a really nice..... people often ask
on recipes and those that don't
know don't give me the answer,
but where did the sugars come from when you use
a sugar substitute it's the dairy lactose is a
sugar it's a type of sugar in milk and cream and
actually that's what people have the allergy to
in in lactose intolerance it's actually a type
of sugar so people that ask about lactose free
ice cream just buy lactose free milk or
lactose free cream then you you're done,
you can even buy lactose free skim milk powder
so there's no reason to make bad ice cream,
even if you are lactose intolerant, just
choose the three specific ingredients that
you need to make high quality professional
grade ice cream like we do on this channel.
I'd like to also welcome all the new subscribers,
loads of you in the last month.... it's like two
and a half thousand of you in the last month which
is incredible, the ninja creamy has got a lot to
do with this so something I want to point out is
as you likely know, the ninja creamy has quite a
following most recipes you'll find are really
quite bad. If you are one of those people that
just wants to make good ice cream, come along on
my journey we're going to make a load of it. As
we increase in subscribers I'm open to lots of new
suggestions so let me know what you want to see in
the comments, I will do my best, I got a huge list
but I'm working through it so thanks for much for
coming with me don't forget to like and subscribe
if you're not and I'll see you next time [Music]